Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Sabera, the White Silver Priestess…
You're one of a kind because
you're different from Gatlantians.
Yet, this is such a crude task.
It's okay.
I'm not concerned about what could happen
to me, as long as I can help you, Your Majesty.
I am Sabera...
...one of a kind...
...and the priestess, who manages
the Comet Metropolis Empire.
Desler Cannon ?
It's similar to the wave motion gun in principle.
When we were trapped within the alternate space,
a similar signature was observed.
If Gatlantis has obtained the Desler Cannon…
So, why me ?
Who else on this ship can I ask ?
What's on your mind ?
You started it.
We can cooperate on this ship if both
of us are honest with each other.
We are one of a kind.
One of a kind…
I wonder…
Any update  ?
Still working on it.
Meeting in Progress
No Entry Permitted
They say our position was being
leaked during the last battle.
Just like Professor what's his name, someone on
the ship might be getting manipulated by the enemy.
Aren't we suspects, too ?
We were away from the Yamato, carrying
out a separate mission on the 11th planet.
Same for what's her face in the sickbay…
...Katsuragi Touko.
Geez, we don't have much time until
we make contact with the White Comet.
We have no proof whether
it's the enemy's main base or not.
Proof…
This is as much detail as we can make out
with the optical sensors at our current distance.
So, that's the White Comet…
His Majesty predicted Desler's rebellion ?
Of course. His Majesty is
aware of Garmillas' moves.
That crook was fooled by his emotion, and tried to destroy the Yamato by sacrificing his own people.
Even if he's a rare sample, our
communication with Mr. Mill was cut off, so…
That's fine.
Let him do as he likes for now.
We've gained enough energy
from Telezart in order to warp.
We'll head for Earth...
...the home to the ship called by Teresa…
That poor planet destined to be destroyed.
I've grown tired of seeing it.
What…was that ?
Ms. Katsuragi, what's wrong ?
Nothing.
Can I help you, umm...?
Yamamoto Akira.
This is sad.
A spy that can't remember my name.
What're you talking about ?
I heard from Lieutenant Keyman...
...that you're a spy.
Don't move.
You aren't going to deny you're a spy ?
If the Lieutenant said so, he's probably right…
…because we are open with each other.
Your trick question was cute.
Do you...like him ?
That emotion will…
That's enough.
Kodai, she's made a move !
All hands, arm yourself with B equipment.
Close all bulkheads.
Currently, Katsuragi Touko is on the run.
She's suspected of being an enemy spy.
Whoever finds her, report to the bridge.
Really ?
I can't believe Touko's the one.
Careful.
If she's a Gatlantis soldier,
she might self-detonate.
Your Majesty…
I'm the White Silver Priestess…
…the only one who manages
the Comet Metropolis Empire.
Are you alright ?
Commander.
Dammit.
Sorry, she got away.
I've got all the cameras monitoring the ship.
It's only a matter of time until we find…
Wha…?
The White Comet…
…the White Comet vanished !
What ?
What happened ?
I don't know.
If the data's correct, it just vanished.
What's this vibration ?
Engine room ?
Gravitational interference
wave detected at 12 o'clock.
Kodai !
Turn 180 degrees, all hands…
We're being pulled in.
Different pattern on the gas surface.
What ?
A powerful gravitational interference wave appears to be emitting from the center of the comet.
That's no natural phenomenon.
It's targeting the Yamato.
They can control this much hyper gravity ?
I knew it.
This is the main base of Gatlantis.
It's like a solar flare.
Even with our wave motion shield,
a direct hit is dangerous.
This feeling again.
Who…who's playing this ?
Just like the Silver White Priestess.
No one else can do this.
I'm Sifar Sabera.
Gatlantians reproduce by cloning...
...but I'm the only one…
Yamato…
…the ship that disturbs his mind,
and brings harm to Gatlantis.
Are you…going to kill me ?
Who's talking to me from there ?
Who ?
I'm Sabera.
No, I am Sabera, the mediator who leads the Comet Metropolis Empire to enlightenment…
…and manages it, according to His Majesty's orders.
…for His Majesty.
Who are you ?
Who am I ?
I'm Sabera, one of a kind.
The gravitational interference wave has weakened.
Now's the time, Shima !
Is this…
A resonance between the two Saberas.
We were careless.
We've never let two pure bodies
come this close before.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty…
Pure bodies are different from us.
Two of them can't coexist…
Your Majesty…
You're one of a kind.
The only human who can punish other humans.
You aren't obeying me.
I'm obeying you.
The last human, Sifar Sabera.
Your Majesty…this is your…
Klaus Keyman…
Shoot...
...before I get caught and start confessing.
Maintain maximum output !
No use !
We're still being pulled in !
We've entered the interior of the White Comet !
That's…
A large fleet of enemy warships.
Shima !
No, I can't stop.
Why aren't they firing ?
Incredible.
Sabera's resonance made
everyone stand to attention.
That's enough of this.
Prepare for a phase-shifting dimensional transposition.
Sabera, what's wrong ?
Sabera…Sabera !
What are you doing ?
You were going to kill me.
Why did you…
Indeed, this is ridiculous.
This feeling…
In a distant past, he…
…he and I suffered from it.
I can never break free.
But it's a warm suffering.
Sabera…
You're not a part of this.
The two are resonating with each other.
At this rate…
Get out…
Everyone, get the hell out !
What is this ?
Is this love…
…which has made me and Zorder suffer ?
Why must we repeat this same cycle ?
Your Majesty...
...Zorder…
You're the White Silver Priestess.
I'm Sifar Sabera.
You know love will lead humans to ruin.
Yes, I know what love is, so do…
No !
I've identified the center of the
gravitational wave that's pulling the Yamato.
Putting the visual analysis on the main panel.
Diameter is 6,800 km,
almost the same size as Mars.
A planet inside a comet ?
Could that be Gatlantis'…
Let's end this.
As I told you before, we're inside your mind.
Stop.
What you're trying to
destroy is not the universe, but...
Stop.
…your own…
The gravitational wave is gone.
Now, get ready to warp !
Warp !
Warp complete.
Engine normal.
Even though Gatlantis has such
a large force, they didn't attack.
We might be insignificant to them.
Gailane, get a new priestess.
How many have there been ?
The copies have restricted memories, so why do they regain the memory of the original, one after another ?
I've contacted Earth HQ.
We should continue our quest.
That massive Gatlantis still wants the power of Telezart, and we must end the seizure.
Episode 12
Astonishing White Comet Empire ? Yamato Breaks Free !
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Shinohara Hiroki:
Yamamoto Akira:
Tsurumi Jiro:
Sawamura Sho:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Hirakawa Daisuke
Tanaka Rie
Komoto Keisuke
Chikaki Yuya
Togire yuku manazashi wa...
Your fading gaze turns to...
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Kurata Masaru:
Hijikata Ryu:
Katsuragi Touko:
Keyman:
Zorder:
Sabera:
Gailane:
Genitz:
Lazera:
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Kiyohito Yoshikai
Ishizuka Unsho
Kaida Yuko
Kamioya Hiroshi
Tezuka Hideaki
Kaida Yuko
Hidekatsu Shibata
Hideyuki
Harasawa Kouki
...Yuuja no tashika na rashinban
...a trusted compass of a warrior
Yakusoku wa nai mama ni...
Without any promise...
...Yatsura mo ikari wo agedasu
...they will weigh anchor in response
Kowarekaketa kono sekai wa...
The half-destroyed world has named...
...Te wo sashinoberu hito no na wo
...the people who can lend a hand
Namari iro no kotae ga...
A lead-colored response...
...Kurayami ni tsumetaku tsukihanasu
...cut coldly through the darkness
Inochi wo tsumuide tokoshie no tami
Spin the thread of life for the everlasting journey
Kibou no kuni e
To the nation of hope
Otoko no sadame ni seigi tsuranuki
Stay faithful to justice in men's destiny
Torawareta ashita wo sukuu no sa
Save the besieged future
Shuuen ni mukaeba itsuka rifujin na sekai ga...
When the end comes near, the unexpected world will...
...Kurenai no sakazuki de otagai no yuuki tataeyou
...cheer both sides with a crimson cup
Hakai to souzou densetsu no kake...
Destruction and creation, and legendary wagers...
...Yatsura mo onaji sa
...fall onto both sides
Tatakai no hibuta
The outbreak of war
Towa ni kirarete honou no okite
It repeats endlessly in a destined blaze
Kodoku to shouri ga korogariochiru...
Loneliness and victory will eventually be known...
...Mekuru meku uchuu no hate made
...throughout dazzling space
Preview
You will eventually betray the Yamato.
You have no such thing
as ideals in your society ?
We're gonna kick their ass !
Tsurumi, break away !
Damn, until the Yamato arrives…
The Yamato has no future unless
you break its curse yourself.
Episode 13
Telezart Landing Operation ? Destroy the Enemy Fleet of Missile Ships !